FERNANDO CORTE VARGAS

Data Analytics Engineer

f.cortevargas@gmail.com

Portfolio

4 +31 6 57 59 88 84

GitHub

Rotterdam, NL

in LinkedIn

SUMMARY

I am a dedicated, motivated, and detail-oriented Analytics Engineer with a deep passion for data and software. With a strong set of programming and design skills gained through relevant work experience, coursework and personal projects, my career goal is to become a well-rounded data professional while continuously expanding my knowledge and skills.

SKILLS -

SQL, dbt, PostgreSQL, AWS, Kubernetes, Data Engineering:

Terraform, Dagster, Docker, Python

ML Engineering: Pandas, TensorFlow, PyTorch, scikit-learn,

Ray RLlib, Azure ML, REST APIs, Sage-

Maker, MLflow

Other: Git, Bash, C++, Unity, C#, LATEX, Agile.

EXPERIENCE

7/2024 - ongoing Data Analytics Engineer

TicketSwap

- · Built and maintained end-to-end data pipelines, with a focus on optimizing the data transformation layer using dbt, Kubernetes and AWS.
- · Applied key data engineering concepts and best practices to deploy and maintain the company's data
- Generated actionable insights by leveraging business intelligence and data analysis tools to drive strategic improvements and decision-making.

7/2021 - 6/2024

Senior Host X TU Delft

- · Lead front desk employee at the sports and culture center of the university. First point of contact for customers and responsible for the handling of complaints and scheduling of other front desk employees.
- · Provide online and on-site support for customers, troubleshooting, and emergency response.

9/2022 - 1/2023 Machine Learning Intern

Viroteg.ai

- · Developed and tested a look-ahead algorithm to enhance the reinforcement learning-based on-the-fly mixed palletizing stacking AI provided by Viroteq.ai.
- · Learned to use Ray RLlib, and learned the basics of Docker and Azure cloud computing services.

EDUCATION -

9/2021 - 6/2024 M.Sc. Cognitive Robotics **Delft University of Technology**

Graduated. Average GPA: 8.1/10.

9/2017 - 1/2021

B.Sc. Aerospace Engineering

Delft University of Technology

Graduated. Minor in Computer Science.

PROJECTS -

1/2024 - ongoing

Plant Mania

Currently developing Plant Mania, a solo-developed web app to manage my plants at home. This web app is a learning exercise to learn about full-stack development, utilizing PostgreSQL for robust database management and Python-based APIs for seamless communication between backend and frontend components.

7/2023 - ongoing

Ofrenda

Currently developing Ofrenda, a solo-developed video game that I took on as a hobby. This video game is a 2D pixel art puzzle platformer, inspired by the Mexican holiday Día de Muertos. Working on the endto-end development with C# using Unity, the design of animated sprites with Aseprite, and the design of gameplay mechanics and levels. Aiming to release the game in the long term.

4/2023 - 7/2023

Retail Robotic Arm Manipulator

Contributed to the software development of a mobile manipulator robot designed to relocate incorrectly placed products on supermarket shelves, in collaboration with Ahold Delhaize. Focused on computer vision and human-robot interaction to ensure safety and promote engagement with customers in retail environments.

LANGUAGES